<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.dancinggoat.articlepage>
  <ArticlePagePublishDate>2023-08-07 22:00:00Z</ArticlePagePublishDate>
  <ArticlePageSummary>
    <![CDATA[Dancing Goat regularly donates money to Children in Africa, a foundation that helps children with food, accommodation, education and others. Create a better world and donate with us.]]>
  </ArticlePageSummary>
  <ArticlePageTeaser>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"637bfdc9-b1f9-4015-8268-459c6b2d5f23"}]]]>
  </ArticlePageTeaser>
  <ArticlePageText>
    <![CDATA[<p id="isPasted">People at Dancing Goat care about other people and their standard of living. Every year, <strong>we donate five thousand dollars to Children in Africa</strong> and we also encourage all our customers to contribute to our public PayPal donation account to help us increase the final amount of money. The Children in Africa foundation <strong>provides food, accommodation, medical service and also education to children from poor regions</strong> in African countries.</p><p><br></p><p>Every month, volunteers from all over the world come to help to Children in Africa camps, where they try to help all children who lack of something and try to narrow the gap in living standards. With the donated money, the foundation buys mainly food and medication.</p><p><br></p><p>Create a better world and donate with us to Children in Africa. <strong>Even a few dollars can improve someone's life.</strong> Any help from you is always appreciated and you have our sincere thanks for every cent you donate.</p><p><br></p><p><a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_donations&amp;business=dancinggoat%40local%2elocal&amp;lc=US&amp;no_note=0&amp;currency_code=USD&amp;bn=PP%2dDonationsBF%3abtn_donateCC_LG%2egif%3aNonHostedGuest"><img alt="Donate" src="https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donate_LG.gif" class="fr-fic fr-dii"></a></p>]]>
  </ArticlePageText>
  <ArticleTitle>Donate with us</ArticleTitle>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>9246d73c-ac38-4318-b31d-d6540369c730</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>DonateWithUs-ib1owx14</CodeName>
      <GUID>294d6b5d-46fd-4c7a-b0b6-99af3472b468</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>8309ebb9-f6d2-44fc-a4fe-27c3903b9a81</ContentItemDataGUID>
</contentitemdata.dancinggoat.articlepage>